Guide to the Jerry Wische JCC Collection, 1936-2021 MS 931
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Jerry Wische JCC Collection
1936-2021
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Wische, Jerry
MS 931
.50 Linear Feet 1 box
This collection is made up of one box containing administrative records, event materials, newsletters and news clippings, correspondence, and media from Jerry Wische's personal collection of Houston Jewish Community Center materials spanning from 1936-2021.
Biographical / Historical
Jerry Wische grew up in Hillside, New Jersey, where he attended Hebrew school at Temple Sinai. After spending a year attending Penn State in the School of Architecture, Wische transferred to the University of Pittsburgh in 1962. The university was across the street from WMHA, which became the JCC, where he got a job leading a group with the Pittsburgh Chapter of Young Judaea. Less than a year after starting, he was asked to be interim director after the previous director left.
After six years working at the Pittsburgh JCC, Wische moved to Houston after he was recruited to be assistant director of the Houston JCC by, then director, Hans Mayer. When Mayer stepped down in 1977 to lead the Jewish Federation, Wische became director.
Jerry Wische retired from the Houston JCC in 2010 after 38 years of service.
Content Description
One box of administrative records, event materials, newsletters and news clippings, correspondence, and media document some activities undertaken by members of the Jewish Community Center from 1936 to 2021.
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open for research without restriction.
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center and requires 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Jerry Wische donated the papers in October 2017.
Arrangement
The materials in this collection have been arranged in five series as follows: Series I: Adminstrative Records; Series II: Correspondence; Series III: Newsletters; Series IV: Pamphlets; Series V: Addenda
Index Terms
Subjects
Jews and Jewish life
Subjects (Persons)
Wische, Jerry
- Series I: Administrative Records
  - Charter Documents for the Young Men and Young Women's Hebrew Association, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - JCC Trustees Meeting and Notes on the JCC Building, 1965-01-05 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - JCC Annual Report 2009 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Series II: Correspondence
  - Invitation to JCC Groundbreaking, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Series III: Newsletters
  - "New Center Under Construction" Newsletters, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Single Professionals Newsletter, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - The Center News Newsletter, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - West Side News Newsletter, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - JCC "The Teen Times" Newsletter, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - The Center News Newsletters, 2003-2007 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - JCC Houston "The Courier" Newsletter, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - J Connections JCC Supplement Newsletter, 2009-2010 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Series IV: Pamphlets
  - Booklet on Proposed JCC Expansion, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Houston Jewish Film Festival Pamphlet, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - JCC Children's Scholarship Ball Pamphlet, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - JCC Celebrating 70 Years Booklet, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Jewish Book and Arts Fair Booklet, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Series V: Addenda
  - JCC Charter Documents (photocopie), 1936-1983 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - JCC campaign for new building, 1963-1967 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - JCC Arts, 1972-2010 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - JCC program guides, 1973-1988 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - The Center News, 1973-2006 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - JCC annual meetings and reports, 1978-2010 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - JCC Book Fair, 1991-2021 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - JCC Maccabi Games, 1999-2008 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - JCC Scholar Ball, 2005-2014 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - JCC Maccabi Games - 19 Stories video cassette (VHS), 1999-08-05-1999-08-11 (Box 1)